<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rstats on A Hugo website</title>
    <link>/tags/rstats/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rstats on A Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/rstats/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using Pagerank to Analyze NBA Games</title>
      <link>/2020/12/09/using-pagerank-to-analyze-nba-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/12/09/using-pagerank-to-analyze-nba-games/</guid>
      <description>library(tidyverse) library(lubridate) library(here) library(igraph) Definitions What is network theory? According to wikipedia,
 Network theory is the study of graphs as a representation of either symmetric relations or asymmetric relations between discrete objects.
 What does PageRank do? It is a measure of “eigenvector centrality”.
 In graph theory, eigenvector centrality (also called eigencentrality or prestige score) is a measure of the influence of a node in a network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Dive into the Kruskal-Wallis Test and its R Code</title>
      <link>/2020/11/27/a-dive-into-the-kruskal-wallis-test-and-its-r-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/11/27/a-dive-into-the-kruskal-wallis-test-and-its-r-code/</guid>
      <description>This is a post about statistical computing.
In this post, I would like to talk about the following things:
 introduce the Kruscal_Wallis test examine how to implement this code in R (stats::kruskal.test, coin::oneway_test, rstatix::kruskal_test is not written in R) examine how to improve the performance of the R code  Introduction Let the data consist of \(N = \sum_{j=1}^{k}n_{j}\) observations from the jth treatmentm j = 1,2,…k.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Tutorial on Bootstrap Confidence Interval - Part II</title>
      <link>/2020/11/13/a-tutorial-on-bootstrap-confidence-interval-part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/11/13/a-tutorial-on-bootstrap-confidence-interval-part-ii/</guid>
      <description>As mentioned in my previous post, we should continue with a parametric bootstrap simulation. In addition, in part II of this tutorial, I would like to demonstrate how to construct a “bootstrap likelihood” as an alternative to empirical likelihood.
Recall the parametric bootstrap resamples from the parametric distribution evaluated at the MLE estimates of the parameters:
\[f_{\hat \mu} \xrightarrow{iid} x^* \xrightarrow{t} \hat\theta^*\] where \(\hat \mu\) is the MLE estimate of the parameter \(\mu\).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Analysis with R: A Take Home Test from a Gaming Startup</title>
      <link>/2020/10/28/data-analysis-with-r-take-home-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/10/28/data-analysis-with-r-take-home-test/</guid>
      <description>I recently finished a take home test from a local start-up. It is my first encounter with such tests, so I think it would be interesting to share my work.
Before we dive in, I would like to say that I probably have made things way more complicated than they need to be. The real
library(plotly)library(tidyverse)library(RColorBrewer)library(rethinking)library(dagitty)library(ggforce)library(car)library(effects)library(wesanderson)Q1: General VisualisationStep 1: data cleaningThe original data is in a messy form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Business Model of a Loyalty Program for Mobile Gamers</title>
      <link>/2020/10/28/the-business-model-of-a-loyalty-program-for-mobile-gamers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/10/28/the-business-model-of-a-loyalty-program-for-mobile-gamers/</guid>
      <description>I would like to share some thoughts on the business model of a local start-up. The basic idea is this: the company will give out cash rewards in exchange for users spending time on this app and playing games in an uninterrupted manner. Because it actually pays, the ratings of the company is quite good on the Google Play Store.
Is this a great business model? I had thought about it carefully.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
